Finding Aid for the Edward East Barthell Lantern Slide Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Edward East Barthell Lantern Slide Collection
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0322
10 linear_feet
Scope and Content Note
This is a collection of 433 lantern slides and glass negatives, exclusive to Vanderbilt University and/or the Nashville, Tennessee area. Lantern slides were invented in 1849, ten years after the invention of the photograph. This medium allowed for viewing photographs and images in an entirely new format, visible to a substantial group of people. Lantern slides were used at Vanderbilt alumni events and contain images that aren’t available in other formats. This particular collection contains lantern slides of group portraits, photographs of buildings, portraits of alumni, portraits of faculty, yearbook portraits, campus maps, tombs, and publications.
Biography of Edward East Barthell
Edward E. Barthell was born in East Nashville, Tennessee, in April 1866. Barthell was the eldest of three sons of Jackson P. Barthell and Fannie Card Barthell. Upon graduating Vanderbilt, he began practicing law and was a prominent member of the Nashville Bar. In 1894, he married Florence E. Freeman and they had four children, of which Edward Barthell Jr. came to work with him in his Chicago law practice, later in his career.
Barthell went to Vanderbilt Law School – graduating class of 1888. As a student he was highly involved and active in the collegiate life. In 1887, he was given the Founder’s Medal and chosen to represent Vanderbilt in an intercollegiate oratory contest. He was also a member of the Kappa Alpha Fraternity.
In 1889 he began practicing law in Tennessee with John Bell Keeble, a classmate and friend. This partnership dissolved because Keeble was appointed the District Attorney for the L & N Railroad. Eventually Barthell began commuting between a Chicago firm and a Nashville firm. However this commute ended in 1915, when he moved to Chicago, and became part of the Barthell, Fitts & Rundall practice, which eventually employed his son Edward Barthell Jr.
Barthell continued to be involved with the Vanderbilt community. In 1905 he was president of the Vanderbilt Alumni Association. He was also a member of the Board of Directors. He was considered one of the most active members of the Vanderbilt Board of Trust. He died May 9, 1937 at the age of 68
- Slides 001 – 018N
  - Administrators (Box 1)
  - Astronomy (Box 1)
  - Athletics (Box 1)
- Slides 019 – 037.1N
  - Athletics (Box 2)
- Slides 038N – 059N
  - Buildings
    - Alumni Hall (Box 3)
    - Barnard Observatory (Box 3)
    - Buttrick Hall (Box 3)
    - Calhoun Hall (Box 3)
    - Composites (Box 3)
    - Dudley Field (Box 3)
    - Faculty Houses (Box 3)
    - Fraternity Houses (Box 3)
    - Galloway Memorial Hospital (Box 3)
    - Garland Hall (Box 3)
- Slides 060 – 078N
  - Buildings
    - Kirkland Hall (Box 4)
    - Kissam Hall (Box 4)
- Slides 079 – 104
  - Buildings
    - Mechanical Engineering Hall (Box 5)
    - Neeley Memorial (Box 5)
    - Old Central (Box 5)
    - Old Gym (Box 5)
    - Peabody College (Box 5)
    - Power House (Box 5)
    - School of Dentistry (Box 5)
    - School of Medicine (Box 5)
    - School of Nursing (Box 5)
    - Science Hall (Box 5)
    - Wesley Hall (Box 5)
    - West Side Row (Box 5)
    - YMCA Building (Box 5)
- Slides 105 – 128N
  - Campus Maps
    - Plat map of Nashville, c1780s (Box 6)
    - Plat map of Nashville, c1790s (Box 6)
    - Plat map of Vanderbilt campus area, c1809 (Box 6)
    - Plat map of Vanderbilt campus area, c1859-1860 (Box 6)
    - Campus map, c1875 (Box 6)
    - Campus map, 1895-1897 (Box 6)
    - Campus map showing plots of land purchased to form Vanderbilt campus, c1896 (Box 6)
    - Student satire of campus map, c1900 (Box 6)
    - Campus map, c1900-1910 (Box 6)
    - Campus plan by Hunt & Hunt, 1902 (Box 6)
    - Campus plan by Kessler & Co., 1905 (Box 6)
    - Variation of campus plan by Kessler & Co., 1905 (Box 6)
    - Campus map from 1913 catalog (Box 6)
    - Downtown Nashville showing Vanderbilt, Peabody and Belmont campuses, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Campus plan by Day & Klauder, 1924 (Box 6)
    - Campus map, c1928-1929 (Box 6)
    - Campus Map, 1941 (Box 6)
    - Campus plan by Edward Stone Company, 1947 (Box 6)
  - Fraternities
    - Delta Kappa Epsilon group portrait, c1920s (Box 6)
    - First Phi Beta Kappa Key, 1776 (Box 6)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Hall, College of William and Mary, c1926 (Box 6)
    - Phi Chi group portrait, circa, 1920s (Box 6)
    - Sigma Alpha Epsilon group portrait, c1900 (Box 6)
    - Sigma Alpha Epsilon group portrait, c1900 (Box 6)
- Slides 130 – 144N
  - Campus Scenes (Box 7)
    - Path to Old Main, pre, 1905 (Box 7)
    - Walkway through campus (Box 7)
    - Campus snow scene with trees (Box 7)
    - Snowy path to Old Main (Box 7)
    - Snow-filled walkway through campus (Box 7)
    - Kissam Hall and McGill Residence surrounded by snow (Box 7)
    - Snow covered walk on campus (Box 7)
    - Snow covered walk on campus with woman standing in background (Box 7)
  - Campus Scenes – Aerials
    - Aerial view of campus (Box 7)
  - Campus Scenes – Composites
    - Composite of various campus scenes titled “Necessities” (Box 7)
  - Campus Scenes – Garland Oak
    - Garland Oak, pre, 1911 (Box 7)
    - New Garland Oak, 19 October 1925 (Box 7)
  - Campus Scenes – Gates
    - Broad Street Entrance, circa, 1900 (Box 7)
    - Broad Street Entrance, 1921 (Box 7)
  - Campus Scenes – Stiles
    - Vanderbilt Stile, circa, 1920s (Box 7)
  - Songs and Yells
    - “Grey Heads, Bald Heads”, (Class of 1917) (Box 7)
    - “Oh, It Was Back in ‘17”, (Class of 1917) (Box 7)
- 147 – 166
  - Statues, Monuments and Tombs
    - Three Bishops Monument (Box 8)
    - Landon Cabell Garland Bust, front and side views (Box 8)
    - Commodore Statue, front and rear views (Box 8)
    - William H. Vanderbilt laying wreath at foot of Commodore Statue (Box 8)
  - Student Activities – Publications
    - Graduation Silhouette (Box 8)
    - Vandy Vampire (Box 8)
    - “March of Time” tribute for alumni reunion (Box 8)
    - “In Memoriam” tribute to deceased alumni (Box 8)
    - Ladies’ Fashion in the 1880s (Box 8)
  - World War I & II
    - World War I ROTC seniors from Fort Oglethorpe (Box 8)
    - World War I student drill company (Box 8)
    - ROTC drill formation on Dudley Field (Box 8)
  - Portraits – Board of Trust
    - Buffington, Eugene Jackson (Box 8)
    - Cason, Charles (Charlie) (Box 8)
    - Cole, Whitefoord (Box 8)
    - Connell, William Phillips (Phil) (Box 8)
    - Davis, Norman H. (Box 8)
- Slides 167 – 183
  - Board of Trust
    - East, Edward H. (Box 9)
    - Edgerton, John Emmet (Edge) (Box 9)
    - Loventhal, Lee Jefferson (Box 9)
    - McReynolds, James Clark (Box 9)
    - Saner, Robert E. Lee (Box 9)
    - White, Horace H. (Box 9)
  - Faculty
    - Faculty Football Team (satire) (Box 9)
    - Divinity Faculty 1881/1882 (composite) (Box 9)
      - Garland, Landon Cabell (Box 9)
      - Summers, Thomas O. (Box 9)
      - Dodd, Thomas J. (Box 9)
      - Shipp, Albert M. (Box 9)
      - Tigert, John J. (Box 9)
      - Granbery, John C. (Bishop) (Box 9)
    - Administration circa 1888 (composite) (Box 9)
    - Arnold, B. W. circa 1888 (Box 9)
    - Ashford, John (Box 9)
    - Ashford, John and Mrs. Emma Louise Hindle Ashford (Box 9)
    - Barnard, Edward Emerson circa 1887 (Box 9)
    - Barnard with Telescope circa 1880s (Box 9)
- Slides 184 – 198N
  - Faculty
    - Barr, Richard Alexander (Box 10)
    - Barr, Richard Alexander and Robert M. McReynolds (Box 10)
    - Brockman, Fletcher S. (Box 10)
    - Broun, William LeRoy (Box 10)
    - Brown, Calvin S. (Box 10)
    - Brown, Charles Summer (Shorty) (Box 10)
    - Brown, Oswald Eugene (Box 10)
    - Buchanan, John Lee (Box 10)
    - Burch, Lucius Edward (Box 10)
    - Carre, Henry Beach (Box 10)
    - Carter, Thomas (Box 10)
    - Crockett, Edmond Irving (Box 10)
    - Crockett, Sidney Scales (Box 10)
    - Daniel, John (Box 10)
    - Dickinson, Jacob McGavock (Box 10)
- Slides 199 – 214
  - Faculty
    - Dudley, William Lofland (Box 11)
    - Dyer, Gustavus Walker (Gus) (Box 11)
    - Eve, Duncan (Box 11)
    - Garland, Landon Cabell (Box 11)
    - Hall, Allen Garland (Box 11)
    - Hall, Fitzgerald (Box 11)
    - Harris, Albert Mason (Box 11)
    - Hollinshead, William H., Mary Boddie, and Maria Boddie (Box 11)
    - Hollinshead, Mrs. Margaret Roberson and daughter Margaret (Box 11)
    - Hollinshead, William H. (Box 11)
    - Howell, Morton Boyte (Box 11)
    - Hume, Alfred (Box 11)
    - Humphreys, Milton W. (Box 11)
- Slides 215 – 232N
  - Faculty
    - Johnson, Edwin Lee (Box 12)
    - Jones, Paul M. (Box 12)
    - Joynes, Edward Southey (Box 12)
    - Keeble, John Bell (Box 12)
    - Kirkland, James Hampton (Box 12)
    - Kirkland, James and Guests in Iris Garden (Box 12)
    - Kirkland, James composite showing various mustaches worn by Kirkland during his tenure as chancellor. (Box 12)
    - Kirkland, Mary Henderson (tentative identification) (Box 12)
    - Lawrence, John and automobile he built (Box 12)
    - Lee, Victor Proctor (Box 12)
    - Leech, J. M. (Box 12)
    - Lipscomb, Andrew A. (Box 12)
    - Little, Charles Edgar (Box 12)
    - Lupton, Nathaniel T. (Box 12)
    - Malone, Thomas H. (Box 12)
    - Malone, Thomas H., Jr. (Box 10)
- Slides 233 – 252N
  - Faculty
    - McGill, John Thomas (Box 13)
    - McGill, John Thomas and Elizabeth Allen (Mrs. John Thomas McGill) (Box 13)
    - McGugin, Daniel E. (Box 13)
    - McGugin, Daniel E. and baby Lucy Ann McGugin (Mrs. Pugh Moore) (Box 13)
    - McTyeire, Holland Nimmons (Bishop) (Box 13)
    - Mims, Edwin (Box 13)
    - Moore, Frederick W. (Box 13)
    - Morgan, William Henry (Box 13)
    - Reinke, Edwin E. (Box 13)
    - Ruddiman, Edsel A. (Box 13)
    - Safford, James Merrill (Box 13)
    - Sarratt, Charles Madison (Box 13)
    - Schuerman, W. H. (Box 13)
    - Seay, Edward Tucker (Box 13)
    - Simmons, Walter Heinman (Box 13)
- Slides 253 – 268
  - Faculty
    - Smelser, Laurence (Box 14)
    - Smith, Charles Forster (Box 14)
    - Snyder, Henry Nelson (Box 14)
    - Stevenson, James H. (Box 14)
    - Stubblefield, David Rankin (Box 14)
    - Summers, Thomas Osgood (Box 14)
    - Tigert, John James (Bishop) (Box 14)
    - Tillett, Wilbur Fisk (Box 14)
    - Tolman, Herbert Cushing (Box 14)
    - Trabue, Charles Clay (Charlie) (Box 14)
    - Vance, Hiram Albert (Box 14)
- Slides 269 – 284N
  - Faculty
    - Vaughn, Stella Scott (Box 15)
    - Vaughn, William J. (Box 15)
    - Waller, Claude (Box 15)
    - Washburn, Charles Campbell (Box 15)
    - Watkins, John Lindsey (Box 15)
    - Williams, Wils (Box 15)
    - Winchell, Alexander (Box 15)
    - Witt, William Henry (Box 15)
    - Young, Bert Edward (Box 15)
  - Staff
    - Alley, James Henry (Cap) (Box 15)
    - Cody, Joshua Crittinden (Josh) (Box 15)
- Slides 285 – 303
  - Staff
    - Collier, Mark (Box 16)
    - Collier, Mark and Chester Clardy (Box 16)
    - Crockett, Sam (Box 16)
    - Douglas, David, Virgil Handley, and Bill (horse) (Box 16)
    - Fields, John (Box 16)
    - Fitzgerald, Bolling (Box 16)
    - Fulton, John (Uncle Remus) (Box 16)
    - Goodall, William (Box 16)
    - Haggard, Mrs. Mary Webb (Box 16)
    - Handley, Virgil and mule-drawn wagon (Box 16)
    - Hart, James Ed (Box 16)
    - Keeble, George (Box 16)
    - Motley, Monroe (Box 16)
    - Schott, Charles (Box 16)
    - Souby, Armand Max (Box 16)
    - Uncle Jack (Box 16)
    - West Side Row Waiters 1900 (Box 16)
- Slides 304 – 322N
  - Portraits
    - Adams, Morton (Box 17)
    - Arthur, Chester A. (Box 17)
    - Bang, Louise Porter (Mrs. John R. Fisher) (Box 17)
    - Barrett, Leland Kelly Willson (Box 17)
    - Beauchamp, William Benjamin (Box 17)
    - Bilbro, Mary Nuckalls (Box 17)
    - Burch, Charles Newell (Charlie) (Box 17)
    - Burch, Robert Lee (Box 17)
    - Cannon, Madge Carroll (Mrs. A. J. Smith) (Box 17)
    - Cohen, Henry Russell (Russ) (Box 17)
    - Cooper, (Tiny) (Box 17)
    - Costen, Charles Bedford (Box 17)
    - Crook, Rachel Lily (Box 17)
    - Crowe, James Richard, Jr. (Box 17)
    - Curry, Irby Rice (Rabbit) (Box 17)
    - Dix, John H. (Box 17)
    - Donaldson, George H. (Box 17)
    - Duncan, Charles Benjamin (Charley) (Box 17)
- Slides 323 – 337N
  - Portraits
    - Dyer, Arthur J. L. (Box 18)
    - Elliston, Mrs. Elizabeth B. (Box 18)
    - Everett, James Dixie (Box 18)
    - Fitzgerald, Oscar P. (Bishop) (Box 18)
    - Fitzgerald, Oscar P. (Bishop) (Box 18)
    - Folk, Joseph Wingate (Box 18)
    - Frierson, Meade Inslee, Jr. (Box 18)
    - Gates, Florena (Mrs. Herman L. Rich) (Box 18)
    - Godchaux, Frank Area (Box 18)
    - Graham, Richard Helm (Box 18)
    - Handly, John Marks White Martin Joseph (Box 18)
    - Harris, William Henry (Box 18)
- Slides 338 – 356
  - Portraits
    - Heath, John (Box 19)
    - Henry, Robert Selph (Box 19)
    - Hines, Richard Percy (Box 19)
    - Hines, Sapho (Box 19)
    - Howell, Alfred Elliot (Box 19)
    - Huang, Jen Lin (Box 19)
    - Johnson, Dora A. (Box 19)
    - Johnson, H.H. (Box 19)
    - Herbert, Joseph Johns (Box 19)
    - Lipscomb, Thomas Ellis (Box 19)
    - Lupton, Kate (Box 19)
    - Group Photo of 1879 Graduating Class (Box 19)
    - Manier, Lt. Emmet Malone (Box 19)
    - Mason, Maria Henderson (Mrs. Felix M. Masey) (Box 19)
    - Massey, Felix Matthias (Box 19)
- Slides 353-367
  - Portraits
    - McCann, Jeff (Box 20)
    - McReynolds, Robert (Box 20)
    - Moore, Nannie Hardin (Bateman) (Box 20)
    - Morgan, Henry W. (Box 20)
    - Newsom, Bessie Wooten (Florence) (Box 20)
    - O’Connor, Myles Powers (Box 20)
    - Oglesby, Lt. Knowles G. (Box 20)
    - Overall, James Elmo (Box 20)
    - Pierce, Franklin (Box 20)
    - Price, Lt. Charles Eugene (Box 20)
    - Price, Lt. Charles Eugene (Box 20)
    - Pusey, Dr. William Allen (Box 20)
    - Pusey, Dr. William Allen (Box 20)
    - Rice, Henry Grantland (Box 20)
- Slides 368-383
  - Portrait
    - Robertson, Lt. Charles Arthur (Box 20)
    - Rodriguez, Alfonso A. (Box 20)
    - Rucker, Barrington A. (Box 20)
    - Ryals, John Bryans Jr (Box 20)
    - Sanders, William Thomas (Box 20)
    - Scarritt, Rev. Charles Wesley (Box 20)
    - Shannon, George Pope (Box 20)
    - Stephens, Lt. Clay Greer (Box 20)
    - Stephens, Gn. John Edmundson (Box 20)
    - Strother, Judge Sidney L. (Box 20)
    - Tate, James A. Jr. (Box 20)
    - Tigert, John James Jr. (Box 20)
    - Timothy, Lt. James Simmons (Box 20)
    - Vaughn, Dr. Harry S. (Box 20)
    - Waller, Benjamin Gibson (Box 20)
    - Young, Elizabeth Potts (Mrs. E.P. Coppedge) (Box 20)
- Slides 384-397
  - Group Portraits
    - Freshman Class Dental, 1915 (Box 21)
    - Sophomore Class Academic & Engineering, 1915 (Box 21)
    - Freshman Class Medical, 1914 (Box 21)
    - Junior Class College of Arts and Sciences, 1916 (Box 21)
    - Freshman Class Academic & Engineering, 1914 (Box 21)
    - Bible Class, 1910 (Box 21)
    - Vanderbilt Co-Eds, 1900 (Box 21)
    - Class of 1899 – Law Department (Box 21)
    - Glee Club, 1893 (Box 21)
    - The Old Oak Club, 1898 (Box 21)
    - The Old Oak Club, 1903 (Box 21)
    - The Old Oak Club, 1914 (Box 21)
    - Owl Club, 1916 (Box 21)
    - Michigan Mass Meeting (unknown date) (Box 21)
- Slides 398-416
  - Group Portraits - Unidentified Groups & Unidentified Portraits
    - Adams Family (Box 22)
    - Adams boys (Box 22)
    - Albes Parks Banta (Box 22)
    - Brigham (Ambrose), Rosa; Burns (Ambrose), Sophie; Guill, Katie Gordon (Box 22)
    - Flippin, Mabelle; Linah, Letty (Box 22)
    - Garland granddaughters (Box 22)
    - Lewis, Bertha; Smith, Louisa (Box 22)
    - Lund, Morsheimer, & Draper with dogs (Box 22)
    - Four Jacks (Box 22)
    - Portrait (two females and one male) (Box 22)
    - Portrait (children: two boys and a girl) (Box 22)
    - Portrait (female) (Box 22)
    - Portrait (young boy) (Box 22)
    - Portrait (male) (Box 22)
    - Portrait (male) (Box 22)
    - Portrait (male) (Box 22)
    - Group portrait (three young males and one boy) (Box 22)
    - Group portrait (19 males) (Box 22)
    - Group portrait (19 males) duplicate (Box 22)
- Slides 417-433
  - VU – Nashville
    - Sketch of Vanderbilt campus pre, 1875 (Box 23)
    - Nashville East of Vanderbilt (Box 23)
    - Nashville, 1888 (Box 23)
    - Horse cars (Box 23)
    - Installation of street cars (Box 23)
    - Girl’s dormitory (Box 23)
    - Residence of Mrs. Elizabeth B. Elliston (Box 23)
    - Residence of Henry Martin Hayes (Box 23)
    - Hermitage (Box 23)
    - Buildings – Hillsboro Road Farm, 1876 (Box 23)
    - Price’s College (Box 23)
    - Residence of William Houston Gordon (Box 23)
    - Rokeby House (Box 23)
    - Scarritt College (Box 23)
    - Ward’s Seminary for Young Ladies (Box 23)
    - West End Methodist Church (Box 23)
    - Unidentified Building (Box 23)
- Slides 434-457
  - National Audubon Societies
    - Yellow Shafted Northern Flicker (Box 24)
    - Ruby Hummingbird (Box 24)
    - North American Wood Duck (Box 24)
    - Unidentified (Box 24)
    - Eastern Bluebird (Box 24)
    - Baltimore Orioles (Box 24)
    - Unidentified (Box 24)
    - Unidentified (Box 24)
    - Green-backed Heron (Box 24)
    - Unidentified (Box 24)
    - Unidentified (Box 24)
    - Scarlet tanager bird, female (green) male (red) (Box 24)
    - Unidentified (Box 24)
    - Rose-breasted Grosbeak, female (yellow) male (black) (Box 24)
    - Baltimore Orioles (Box 24)
    - Unidentified (Box 24)
    - Brown Falcon (Box 24)
    - Unidentified (Box 24)
    - Blue birds (Box 24)
    - American Restart (female and male) (Box 24)
    - Unidentified (Box 24)
    - Unidentified (Box 24)
    - Unidentified (Box 24)
    - Unidentified (Box 24)
- Slides 458-483
  - National Audubon Societies/French WWI
    - Unidentified (Box 25)
    - Men with dogs (2) (Box 25)
    - Unidentified land (Box 25)
    - Unidentified (Box 25)
    - Unidentified men (Box 25)
    - Unidentified men (Box 25)
    - Unidentified men + plane (Box 25)
    - Unidentified soldier (Box 25)
    - Unidentified farmers (Box 25)
    - Unidentified males (Box 25)
    - Train (Box 25)
    - Three soldiers in a field (Box 25)
    - Wagons with logs (Box 25)
    - Destroyed bridge (Box 25)
    - German document – Imperial German government of Belgium (Box 25)
    - Military hospital – Verdun (Box 25)
    - Portrait of nine men + Prime Minister of France (Box 25)
    - Dormans, France in ruins (Box 25)
    - Fort Douaumont in ruins (Box 25)
    - Panorama of wire fence at the Battle of Souain (Box 25)
    - Proclamation of Kaiser Wilhelm II, French & German translations (Box 25)
    - Port Challes Les Eaux (Box 25)
    - Dorman (Box 25)
    - Portrait of Chateau Thierry (Box 25)
    - Paris ambulances (Box 25)
    - Somali’s in camp (Box 25)
- Slides 484-492
  - French/WWI
    - Proclamation October 12,915 – General Von Bissing (Box 25)
    - Speech by Monsieur Ribot & Monsieur Paul Deschanel (Box 25)
    - An [undecipherable] village, in the province of the Oise (Box 25)
    - Soldier’s encampment in the village of Jussy (Box 25)
    - German prisoners (Box 25)
    - A church in the village of the Brides-les-Bains (Box 25)
    - French and German graves (Box 25)
    - Airplanes (Box 25)
    - German proclamation July 20, 1912 (Box 25)
- Slides 493-517
  - French/WWI
    - 96 year old Corporal (Box 27)
    - Military graves (Box 27)
    - Relief troops near Verdun, France (Box 27)
    - Building in ruins in Ypres, France (Box 27)
    - Dentis Rocheford (Box 27)
    - Soldier farming (Box 27)
    - Proclamation date Dec. 1914 (Box 27)
    - German tomb (Box 27)
    - Movie showing for soldiers and civilians (Box 27)
    - Soldier receiving a medal (Box 27)
    - English convoy (Box 27)
    - Mountain range in Germany (Box 27)
    - Evacuees camp, France (Box 27)
    - Aid committee for the refugees (Box 27)
    - The grape harvest (Box 27)
    - Strasburg/Alsace (Box 27)
    - Cattle (Box 27)
    - Unknown men (Box 27)
    - Unknown men + one woman (YMCA logo) (Box 27)
    - Unknown man + woman (YMCA logo) (Box 27)
    - Some horses (Box 27)
    - The veterans of ’70 in Alsace (Box 27)
    - Proclamation of Kaiser Wilhelm II (Box 27)
    - Group of French and English officers in the Oise Valley (Box 27)
    - YMCA, unknown city (Box 27)
- Slides 518-541
  - French/WWI
    - Soldiers lined up (Box 28)
    - High ranking soldiers (Box 28)
    - Man and woman walking alongside two horses (Box 28)
    - Soldiers in a boat (Box 28)
    - Soldiers (Box 28)
    - Arles amphitheater in Rome (Box 28)
    - French soldiers (Box 28)
    - Wagon pulling a cannon (Box 28)
    - Unknown house interior (Box 28)
    - Unknown woman (Box 28)
    - Naval officers (Box 28)
    - YMCA organist + singers, performing (Box 28)
    - YMCA (Box 28)
    - 369th Infantry Regiment (USA) (Box 28)
    - Unknown male portrait (Box 28)
    - 3 men of the 369th Infantry Regiment (USA) (Box 28)
    - Man/soldier being taken into Red Cross facility (Box 28)
    - Unknown men gathered in unknown place (Box 28)
    - Unknown boulder (Box 28)
    - Slaughter house (Box 28)
    - Soldiers gathering (Box 28)
    - Portrait of Pierre Lotti (French author) (Box 28)
    - Police order regarding the consumption of the bread in the Department of the Seine (Box 28)
    - General [Louis] Franchet d’Esperey & General Edouard Castelnau (Box 28)
- Slides 542-566
  - French/WWI
    - Fort Souville (Box 29)
    - Reims, France – Joan of Arc statue in Paris Square (Box 29)
    - Moirement, Marne encampment (Box 29)
    - Encampment in Alsace, France (Box 29)
    - Ghurka regiment (Box 29)
    - Ski troops (Box 29)
    - Slaughterhouse (Box 29)
    - German grave (tomb) – Joulon-Heurtebise Forest (Box 29)
    - German grave (tomb) – Joulon-Heurtebise Forest (Box 29)
    - Rest shelters/cagnas (Box 29)
    - A camouflaged gun battery in action (Box 29)
    - A family with mechanized farm equipment (Box 29)
    - 24 soldiers (Box 29)
    - Mountain soldiers at a stone cross (Box 29)
    - Marne, France (Box 29)
    - Unidentified entrance to unidentified structure (Box 29)
    - Railroad cars/wagons (Box 29)
    - Wagon and bicycles (Box 29)
    - Boulders (Box 29)
    - Sentheim, France – distribution of prizes (Box 29)
    - The return of [?] on a farm in Lorraine (Box 29)
    - Camp at Chalons (Box 29)
    - Coming out of a factory (Box 29)
    - Toulon: women of the Red Cross & [medical?] personnel (Box 29)
    - Man on a wagon (Box 29)
- Slides 567-591
  - French/WWI
    - University section of Rheims – collection of ruins (Box 30)
    - The little Alsatian presents flowers to General Petain (Box 30)
    - Several Tonkin soldiers (Box 30)
    - Notre Dame Chapel of Haut (Box 30)
    - Army & Navy – order of General, issued in 1914 (Box 30)
    - Aix-les-Baines, the thermal establishment (Box 30)
    - Aix-les-Baines – general view (Box 30)
    - Army & Navy – order of General mobilization (Box 30)
    - Speeches from the Republique Francaise (newspaper) (Box 30)
    - German side (Box 30)
    - Saint Amarin – general view (Box 30)
    - Bombardment of Paris near the Gare de l’Est (Box 30)
    - Last autograph declaration of Kaiser Wilhelm II (Box 30)
    - Proclamation of German Emperor Kaiser Wilhelm (Box 30)
    - In Meurthe-et-Moselle (Box 30)
    - The sultan of Rabat (Box 30)
    - English camp, near Moussy (Box 30)
    - French School for Alsatian students (Box 30)
    - Christmas in reconquered Alsace (Box 30)
    - Dieulouard: the theater [visits] the army-arrival of Sarah Bernhardt (Box 30)
    - Mondemont Castl in Marne region (Box 30)
    - Ruins in the vicinity of Verdun (Box 30)
    - Grave of aviator – Pégour (?) (Box 30)
    - Soldiers/shepherds (Box 30)
    - Group of officers – in the Meuse, France (Box 30)